Simon Fraser University Women's Centre fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
- Reference files, 1972 - 1992; F-40-6; 28 cm of textual records 9 sound recordings; Physical description: series includes 9 sound recordings stored on 7 audio cassettes (originals).
  Series consists of publications and other documents collected by the Women's Centre and compiled as a women-centred information and library resource. The Women's Centre Library acquires and maintains books, journal subscriptions and vertical files accessible to all visitors to the Centre, while women who pay membership dues have borrowing privileges. Documents include reports, publications, pamphlets, newspaper clippings, papers, presentations, and audio recordings of interviews, talks and presentations.
  In the initial arrangement of the fonds (2001), files were organized alphabetically. With the addition of accruals in 2009, this order is no longer apparent. Post-2001 accruals (from file 16 onwards) were simply added chronologically.
  - Sexual Harassment - reps from AUCE, BCGEU, CUPE summer '81 series, 1981; F-40-6-0-0-0-1 (Audio cassette OBJ-3107)
    Association of University and College Employees, Local 2; British Columbia Government Employees Union; Canadian Union of Public Employees; Sound recordings
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: C-40-6-0-16.1 orig., F-40-item1.
  - The Automation of Automation - Maggie Benston summer '82 series, 7 July 1982; F-40-6-0-0-0-2 (Audio cassette OBJ-3108)
    Benston, Maggie; Sound recordings
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: C-40-6-0-17.1 orig., F-40-item2.
  - Women and Science - Marion Lowe summer '82 series, 21 July 1982; F-40-6-0-0-0-3 (Audio cassette OBJ-3109)
    Lowe, Marian; Sound recordings
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: C-40-6-0-18.1 orig., F-40-item3.
  - St. John's Women's Centre Interview with Beth, Coordinator, [ca 1985]; F-40-6-0-0-0-4 (Audio cassette OBJ-3110)
    Sound recordings
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: C-40-6-0-19.1 orig., F-40-item4.
  - International Women's Day - P. Jewett, Aya, B.Blakeley, 8 March 1990; F-40-6-0-0-0-5 (Audio cassette OBJ-3111)
    Jewett, Pauline; B. Blakey; Sound recordings
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: C-40-6-0-20.1 orig., F-40-item5.
  - Plain Words. Sheila McFadzean: SFU Women's Centre, 9 September 1992; F-40-6-0-0-0-6 (Audio cassette OBJ-3112)
    Sheila McFadzean; Sound recordings
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: C-40-6-0-21.1 orig., F-40-item6.
  - Plain Words. Malgorzata Dubiel: Barbie Hates Math, 28 October 1992; F-40-6-0-0-0-8 (Audio cassette OBJ-3113)
    Malgorzata Dubiel; Sound recordings
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: C-40-6-0-22.1 orig., F-40-item7.
  - Plain Words. Kate Braid: Women in Trades, 16 September 1992; F-40-6-0-0-0-7 (Audio cassette OBJ-3112)
    Braid, Kate; Sound recordings
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-40-item6.
  - Plain Words. Patricia O'Hagan: Harassment Policy at SFU, 4 November 1992; F-40-6-0-0-0-9 (Audio cassette OBJ-3113)
    Patricia O'Hagan; Sound recordings
  - Abortion, 1982; F-40-6-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 40-12)
  - Battered women, 1981 - 1985; F-40-6-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 40-12)
  - Child care, 1975 - 1983; F-40-6-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 40-12)
  - Concerned citizens for Choice on Abortion, 1981 - 1983; F-40-6-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 40-12)
  - Guide to the B.C. Women's Movement, 1975 - 1976; F-40-6-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 40-12)
  - Health issues, 1974 - 1983; F-40-6-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 40-12)
  - Housing - Lower Mainland and Vancouver, 1980 - 1982; F-40-6-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 40-12)
  - Pornography, 1983 - 1987; F-40-6-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 40-12)
  - Rape relief, 1975 - 1983; F-40-6-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 40-12)
  - Sexual Assault Recovery Anonymous, 1985; F-40-6-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 40-12)
  - Service, Office and Retail Workers Union of Canada, 1976 - 1983; F-40-6-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 40-12)
  - Women's Rally for Action, 1976; F-40-6-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 40-12)
  - Women at SFU, 1972 - 1975; F-40-6-0-0-13 (Archival box - small 40-13)
  - Women at SFU, 1977 - 1978; F-40-6-0-0-14 (Archival box - small 40-13)
  - Women's groups - general, 1975 - 1984; F-40-6-0-0-15 (Archival box - small 40-13)
  - Lower Mainland Childcare Worker Salaries and Benefits Survey - returns, vol. 1, 1987; F-40-6-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 40-8)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-40-5-0-0-14.
  - Lower Mainland Childcare Worker Salaries and Benefits Survey - returns, vol. 2, 1987; F-40-6-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 40-8)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-40-5-0-0-15.
  - Lower Mainland Childcare Worker Salaries and Benefits Survey - report, 1987; F-40-6-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 40-8)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-40-5-0-0-16.
  - Nightline, 1991; F-40-6-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 40-25)
  - The Creation of a Women's Centre - by Pat Maika, 1976; F-40-6-0-0-20 (Archival box - standard 40-25)
  - Surviving: a Woman's Guide to Carleton University (and Life!) (1981), F-40-6-0-0-21 (Archival box - standard 40-25)
  - Networking Directory: Women's Organizations in the Lower Mainland (1988), F-40-6-0-0-22 (Archival box - standard 40-25)
- British Columbia Federation of Women (BCFW) records, 1976 - 1986; F-40-7; 37 cm of textual records; British Columbia Federation of Women
  The British Columbia Federation of Women (BCFW) was founded in 1974 as an umbrella group of women's organizations. Its objective was to bring about women's liberation through fundamental social change, providing a provincial network of support, information- and resource-sharing, and coordinated action. Groups joined as affiliate members and were organized into regional units; federation-wide matters were overseen by the Coordinating Collective, several standing committees (Finance, Communications and Convention), and various ad hoc committees established to address specific issues and projects. At the Annual General Convention delegates from each of the regions elected committee members and voted on policy resolutions. The BCFW disbanded in 1989.
  Series consists of records made or received by the Women's Centre in its capacity as a member of the British Columbia Federation of Women (BCFW). The SFU Women's Centre was an affiliate member of the BCFW in the Lower Mainland Region. As the BCFW disbanded in 1989, it made a donation to the SFU Women's Centre Development Fund of $1600. This money along with other private donations to the Women's Centre is intended to support work which is feminist and activist in nature but which falls outside the scope of the Centre's usual operations. The Women's Centre Development fund is not used for ongoing operating expenses of the Women's Centre.
  Activities documented in this series include annual BCFW conventions; meetings of the Coordinating Collective, the Lower Mainland Region, and the finance committee; correspondence with various action committees (including the Structure Committee, Rights of Lesbians Committee, Women and Prisons Committee, Women's Heath Committee, Women Against Violence Against Women Committee, and Human Rights Committee); budget planning, grant applications, and accounts management; administration of membership applications, renewals and correspondence; and publications and public relations. Records consist of constitution and policy handbook; correspondence; agendas, minutes and meeting support papers; reports and proposals; financial statements, ledgers and daybooks; membership lists and records; and BCFW newsletters, publications and brochures.
  Note that some of these records were information copies received by the Women's Centre as an affiliate member of the BCFW; others, however, appear to be the original records of the BCFW itself (e.g. some of the financial and membership records).
  The arrangment of the series into five sub-series was supplied by the archivist in order to facilitate intellectual access to the material. The sub-series are organized to group records that were generated by similar functions and activities.
  No further accruals to this series or any of its sub-series is expected.
  Other records relating to the BCFW can be found in other fonds held by the Archives. See also:
  - F-45, Working Women Unite fonds, series 2 (BCFW records, 1977-1982).
  - F-82, Ellen Frank fonds, series 2 (BCFW. 1975-1986)
  - F-111, Kathleen Hudson Women's Bookstore Collection, series 5 (BCFW records, 1974-1982).
  - F-134, Press Gang Printers fonds, series 8 (BCFW files, 1977-1988).
  - BCFW financial records, 1977 - 1985; F-40-7-1; 13 cm of textual records
    Sub-series consists of records relating to BCFW funding and financial management. Activities documented include meetings of the Finance Committee, budget planning and grant applications, and the tracking of accounts and transactions. Records include agendas and minutes; correspondence; budgets, reports and proposals; grant applications and supporting documentation; financial statements, ledgers and daybooks.
    - Financial committee minutes and correspondence, 1978 - 1982; F-40-7-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 40-9)
    - Financial committee minutes and correspondence, 1980 - 1981; F-40-7-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 40-9)
    - Financial committee minutes and correspondence, 1983 - 1984; F-40-7-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 40-9)
    - Finances, 1982 - 1983; F-40-7-1-0-4 (Archival box - standard 40-9)
    - Finances, 1984 - 1985; F-40-7-1-0-5 (Archival box - standard 40-9)
    - Grants and applications, 1977 - 1980; F-40-7-1-0-6 (Archival box - standard 40-9)
    - Grants and applications, 1981 - 1983; F-40-7-1-0-7 (Archival box - standard 40-9)
    - Grants and applications, 1983; F-40-7-1-0-8 (Archival box - standard 40-9)
    - Grants and applications, 1984; F-40-7-1-0-9 (Archival box - standard 40-9)
    - Financial daybook, 1977 - 1980; F-40-7-1-0-10 (Archival box - standard 40-9)
    - Financial daybook, 1980 - 1981; F-40-7-1-0-11 (Archival box - standard 40-9)
    - Financial daybook, 1981 - 1985; F-40-7-1-0-12 (Archival box - standard 40-9)
    - Ledger, 1981 - 1982; F-40-7-1-0-13 (Archival box - standard 40-9)
  - BCFW Lower Mainland Region records, 1977 - 1986; F-40-7-2; 4 cm of textual records
    Sub-series consists of records relating to the activities of the Lower Mainland Region of the BCFW, the section in which the Women's Centre participated as an affiliate member of the Federation. Activities documented include meetings of representatives from the regional groups and correspondence with BCFW committees and other Regions. Records include agendas, minutes and meeting support papers; correspondence and reports.
    - Minutes and correspondence, 1977 - 1979; F-40-7-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 40-10)
    - Minutes and correspondence, 1980; F-40-7-2-0-2 (Archival box - standard 40-10)
    - Minutes and correspondence, 1981; F-40-7-2-0-3 (Archival box - standard 40-10)
    - Minutes and correspondence, 1982; F-40-7-2-0-4 (Archival box - standard 40-10)
    - Minutes and correspondence, 1983; F-40-7-2-0-5 (Archival box - standard 40-10)
    - Minutes and correspondence, 1984 - 1986; F-40-7-2-0-6 (Archival box - standard 40-10)
  - BCFW membership records, 1976 - 1986; F-40-7-3; 10 cm of textual records
    Sub-series consists of records relating to the administration and maintenance of BCFW membership. Groups applied for membership through the Regional section and fees were determined by a formula based on number of women in the affiliate organization. Activities documented include membership applications and correspondence with members concerning renewals and fees. Records include correspondence, member lists, committee lists, and regional membership logs with fee calculations.
    - Membership lists, 1976 - 1983; F-40-7-3-0-1 (Archival box - standard 40-10)
    - Standing committee lists, 1979 - 1981; F-40-7-3-0-2 (Archival box - standard 40-10)
    - Membership coordinator, 1976 - 1983; F-40-7-3-0-3 (Archival box - standard 40-10)
    - Membership correspondence, 1976 - 1981; F-40-7-3-0-4 (Archival box - standard 40-10)
    - Membership correspondence, 1982; F-40-7-3-0-5 (Archival box - standard 40-10)
    - Membership correspondence, 1983 - 1984; F-40-7-3-0-6 (Archival box - standard 40-10)
    - Membership correspondence, 1986; F-40-7-3-0-7 (Archival box - standard 40-10)
    - Region membership records - Region 1 Atlin-Skeena, 1978 - 1983; F-40-7-3-0-8 (Archival box - standard 40-10)
    - Region membership records - Region 4 Fort George-Omineca, 1978 - 1980; F-40-7-3-0-9 (Archival box - standard 40-10)
    - Region membership records - Region 5 Fraser Valley, 1978 - 1981; F-40-7-3-0-10 (Archival box - standard 40-10)
    - Region membership records - Region 6 Lower Mainland, 1978 - 1982; F-40-7-3-0-11 (Archival box - standard 40-10)
    - Region membership records - Region 7 North Island, 1978 - 1982; F-40-7-3-0-12 (Archival box - standard 40-10)
    - Region membership records - Region 8 Okanagan Kamloops, 1978 - 1984; F-40-7-3-0-13 (Archival box - standard 40-10)
    - Region membership records - Region 9 Peace River, 1979 - 1980; F-40-7-3-0-14 (Archival box - standard 40-10)
    - Region membership records - Region 10 Prince Rupert, 1979 - 1981; F-40-7-3-0-15 (Archival box - standard 40-10)
    - Region membership records - Region 11 South Island, 1978 - 1982; F-40-7-3-0-16 (Archival box - standard 40-10)
    - Region membership records - Region 12 West Kootenays, 1979 - 1983; F-40-7-3-0-17 (Archival box - standard 40-10)
  - BCFW organization records, 1978 - 1986; F-40-7-4; 9 cm of textual records
    Sub-series consists of records relating to the governance and internal organization of the BCFW. Activities documented include the development of BCFW policies, procedures and organizational structure; Annual General Conventions; and meetings of the Coordinating Collective and Convention Planning Committee. Records include constitution and policy handbook; agendas, minutes, and meeting support papers; and correspondence, proposals and reports.
    - Constitution and Policy Handbook, 1982 - 1983; F-40-7-4-0-1 (Archival box - standard 40-8)
    - Coordinating Collective minutes, 1980 - 1984; F-40-7-4-0-2 (Archival box - standard 40-8)
    - Convention Planning committee, 1983; F-40-7-4-0-3 (Archival box - standard 40-8)
    - Annual convention, 1978; F-40-7-4-0-4 (Archival box - standard 40-8)
    - Annual convention, 1979; F-40-7-4-0-5 (Archival box - standard 40-8)
    - Annual convention, 1980; F-40-7-4-0-6 (Archival box - small 40-11)
    - Annual convention, 1981; F-40-7-4-0-7 (Archival box - small 40-11)
    - Annual convention, 1983; F-40-7-4-0-8 (Archival box - small 40-11)
    - Annual convention, 1986; F-40-7-4-0-9 (Archival box - small 40-11)
  - BCFW communications files, 1976 - 1983; F-40-7-5; 3 cm of textual records
    Sub-series consists of records relating to the public communication of BCFW activities and organization. Records include newsletters, publications and brochures.
    - Newsletter, 1976 - 1982; F-40-7-5-0-1 (Archival box - small 40-11)
    - Publications, 1983; F-40-7-5-0-2 (Archival box - small 40-11)
    - Brochure, [ca 1980]; F-40-7-5-0-3 (Archival box - small 40-11)
- Liaison and cooperation files, 1978 - 1999; F-40-8; 25 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records relating to the Women's Centre's interaction and work with outside organizations, in particular, the B.C. and Yukon Association of Women's Centres and the Women's Studies Student Union at SFU. Records include reports, minutes, newsletters, correspondence and other documents.
  This series was added to the fonds in 2009 to accommodate accruals. Its arrangement into two sub-series was provided by the archivist in order to faciliate intellectual access to the records, with separate sub-series for records relating to work with other women's centre (sub-series 1) and with the Women's Studies Student Union (sub-series 2).
  - Women's centres, 1986 - 1999; F-40-8-1; 24 cm of textual records
    Sub-series consists of records relating to the SFU Women's Centre's interaction with other women's centres. See access points for the list of organizations. Records include reports, minutes, correspondence, newsletters, and other documents.
    British Columbia and Yukon Association of Women's Centres; Campbell River Women's Centre; British Columbia Institute of Technology Women's Centre; Camosun College Women's Centre; Nanaimo Women's Resources Society
    - BC and Yukon Association of Women's Centres -- reports from annual general meetings, vol. 1, 1986 - 1998; F-40-8-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 40-26)
    - BC and Yukon Association of Women's Centres -- reports from annual general meetings, vol. 2, 1986 - 1998; F-40-8-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 40-26)
    - BC and Yukon Association of Women's Centres -- policies of the association, 1989; F-40-8-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 40-26)
    - BC and Yukon Association of Women's Centres -- general correspondence, vol. 1, 1990 - 1999; F-40-8-1-0-4 (Archival box - standard 40-26)
    - BC and Yukon Association of Women's Centres -- general correspondence, vol. 2, 1990 - 1999; F-40-8-1-0-5 (Archival box - standard 40-26)
    - BC and Yukon Association of Women's Centres -- general correspondence, vol. 3, 1990 - 1999; F-40-8-1-0-6 (Archival box - standard 40-27)
    - BC and Yukon Association of Women's Centres -- issues of "Newsflash", 1991 - 1993; F-40-8-1-0-7 (Archival box - standard 40-27)
    - BC and Yukon Association of Women's Centres -- Korbin Commission submission, 1993; F-40-8-1-0-8 (Archival box - standard 40-27)
    - BC and Yukon Association of Women's Centres -- 1993 annual general meetings, vol. 1, F-40-8-1-0-9 (Archival box - standard 40-27)
    - BC and Yukon Association of Women's Centres -- 1993 annual general meetings, vol. 2, F-40-8-1-0-10 (Archival box - standard 40-27)
    - National Conference of Women's Centres, 1991; F-40-8-1-0-11 (Archival box - standard 40-27)
    - Campbell River Women's Centre, 1993 - 1995; F-40-8-1-0-12 (Archival box - standard 40-27)
    - BCIT Women's Centre, 1994; F-40-8-1-0-13 (Archival box - standard 40-27)
    - Camosun College Women's Centre, 1994; F-40-8-1-0-14 (Archival box - standard 40-27)
    - Nanaimo Women's Resources Society, 1996; F-40-8-1-0-15 (Archival box - standard 40-27)
  - Women's Studies Student Union files, 1978 - 1991; F-40-8-2; 1 cm of textual records
    Sub-series consists of records relating to the establishment, organization and operation of the Women's Studies Student Union at SFU. Records include minutes, constitution, correspondence and other documents.
    Women's Studies Student Union
    - Women's Studies Student Union, 1978 - 1991; F-40-8-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 40-27)